tunein.com 2015-06-27

# TuneIn Radio Privacy

This Privacy Policy was last updated on March 3, 2015.

##  TUNEIN, INC. PRIVACY POLICY 

Welcome to TuneIn. This Privacy Policy is effective for TuneIn, Inc. (“TuneIn”, “we”, “us” and/or “our”) and is incorporated by reference into the TuneIn Terms of Service and End User License Agreement. 

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform users of the TuneIn Service (as defined below) about the information that we collect through the TuneIn Service, how we use that information and the ways users can control how that information is used or shared. The entire policy can be found below. For information about users’ obligations and use of the TuneIn Service, please see our Terms of Service and End User License Agreement. 

We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Policy and update it accordingly when there is a change to our business practices, our users’ needs, and to comply with regulatory and legal requirements. Please check this page periodically for updates. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy here and notify you by email or by means of a notice on the Site (as defined below) and/or the Applications (as defined below). 

The "TuneIn Service" consists of: (a) our audio guide service offering end users access to a selection of indexed radio stations, podcasts, sports, news and other content (the “TuneIn Guide”), whether available through our website located at www.tunein.com (the “Site”) or through any software applications made available for mobile devices (“Guide Applications”); (b) our platform for content streaming that enables sharing of live and recorded audio content (“TuneIn OpenMic”), whether available through the Site or through any software applications made available for mobile devices (the “OpenMic Applications,” and collectively with the Guide Applications, the “Applications”); (c) all software (including the Software, as defined below), external players, buttons and widgets, data, text, images, sounds, video, graphics and photos made available by TuneIn through any of the foregoing (collectively referred to as the "Content"), and (d) any updates, new versions, new releases, additional features and functionality that TuneIn may offer in connection with the foregoing. 

## The types of information we collect

When you interact with the TuneIn Service, we may collect Personal Information (as defined below) and other information from you as described below. 

“Personal Information” means information that alone or when in connection with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you, such as: name, address, email address or phone number. We do not consider personally identifiable information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not allow a third party to easily identify a specific individual. 

## Information you give us 

To enable you to enjoy certain features of the TuneIn Service, we collect certain types of information, including Personal Information, during your interactions with the TuneIn Service. By using the TuneIn Service, you are authorizing us to gather, parse, and retain data related to the provision of the TuneIn Service. 

For example, we collect information, including Personal Information, when you: 

  * Register to use our TuneIn Service;
  * Login with social networking credentials; 
  * Participate in polls, contests, surveys or other features of the TuneIn Service, or respond to offers or advertisements on the TuneIn Service; 
  * Communicate with us; and
  * Sign up to receive email newsletters.

When you register to use the TuneIn Service, we ask you to provide certain information, which includes your name, email address, birth year, gender, zip or postal code and/or other geographic information, as well as a password for your account. By voluntarily providing us with Personal Information or other information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you provide any Personal Information or other information, you acknowledge and agree that such Personal Information may be transferred from your current location to our offices and servers and the authorized third parties located in the United States thus making your Personal Information subject to US law. 

## Following, Followers and other Public Information

The TuneIn Service is designed to help you discover, share and respond to content. Some of the information you provide us is information that is made public. This includes not only the stations, content or people you follow, your echoes, the content you echo or share, your followers, and the metadata provided, such as when you follow, and other information that results from your use of the TuneIn Service (collectively “Public Information”). 

The stations, content or people you follow will be public, but we give you settings to make your following lists more private if you want. However, if you registered for the TuneIn Service prior to May 7, 2014, your following lists will be private, but your following lists will be made public once you sign in to your account. You can change your settings to make your following lists private at any time by changing your profile settings. 

When other people use the TuneIn Service, they may store and share information about you and others that they have, such as when they upload and manage their invites and contacts. 

## Finding you on the TuneIn Service

Your Public Information may be seen. For instance, your profile or screen name may be searchable by search engines just like with many common social media services. 

You may choose to upload your address book provided that you have the consent of the individuals whose information is included in your address book so that we can help you find other users you know. If you choose to upload your address book, you represent that you have the consent of the individuals whose information is included in your address book. Other users may do the same. We may later suggest people to follow based on your imported address book contacts, which you can delete at any time. We receive information about you from your friends and others, such as when they upload your contact information, tag or include a reference to you in an echo. 

To make it easier for your friends to find you, we allow anyone to search by name or email or when a user connects through a social media account on TuneIn. Users may also find you by looking at following lists that other users have chosen to make public. 

## Automatic Data Collection

_Listening and Usage Activity_ : The TuneIn service observes your listening and usage activity. We collect information about stations, favorites, artists, channels, conversations and tracks you have listened to or in which you have expressed an interest. We receive data about you whenever you use the TuneIn Service, such as the sites visited, when you look at another user's profile, echo, search for a friend or a station, click on, view, purchase or otherwise interact with content or materials available by TuneIn or through the TuneIn Service. 

_Social connect information_ : When you choose to connect your social media account to your account profile, we collect Personal Information from that social media website. For example, when you connect your Facebook account, we may collect the Personal Information you have made publicly available in Facebook, such as your name, profile picture, cover photo, username, gender, friend networks, age range, locale, friend list, and any other information you have made public. We may also obtain other non-public information from the social network website with your permission. 

_Information about your computer or device_ : We may also collect information about the computer, mobile or other devices you use to access or use the TuneIn Service. For example, our servers receive and record information about your computer, browser or device, including potentially your IP address, device ID, operating system, browser type, and other software or hardware information. If you access the TuneIn Service from a mobile or other device, unless you register, we may assign a unique device identifier for that device. 

_Location-based information_ : We do not collect your zip code, postal code, city or country unless you choose to provide this information to us at registration. Your general geo-location may be collected at regular intervals if you use the TuneIn Service on your mobile device or through the Site. We collect this information to provide content and services that are customized for your geographic area. 

_Tracking technology_ : We or our third party advertising partners use what are commonly called "cookies" or “tracking pixels”. A cookie is a piece of information that the computer that hosts our Site gives to your browser when you access the Site. These cookies help us improve the TuneIn Service, provide additional functionality to the Site and help us analyze Site usage more accurately. For instance, our Site may set a cookie on your browser that allows you to access the Site without needing to remember and then enter a password more than once during a visit to the Site. We may also be able to capture other data such as searches conducted and results, date, time, and connection speed. In all cases in which we use cookies, we will not collect Personal Information except with your permission. On most web browsers, you will find a “help” section on the toolbar. Please refer to this section for information on how to receive notification when you are receiving a new cookie and how to turn cookies off. We recommend that you leave cookies turned on because they allow you to take advantage of some of the Site’s features. Third parties, including advertisers and third-party advertising companies, whose products or services are accessible or advertised via the TuneIn Service may also use cookies, and we advise you to check their privacy policies for information about their cookies and other privacy practices. Third parties on the TuneIn Service may also use cookies to track your online activities across websites over time to provide interest-based advertising. For more information on how to opt-out of such tracking, please visit www.aboutads.info/choices. 

One of the third party services that we use to track activity related to the TuneIn Service, e.g. by placing cookies, is Google Analytics. We may use third-party vendors, including Google, who use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past activity on our websites and applications, including Google Analytics for Display Advertising. If you don't want any information to be collected and used by Google Analytics, you can install an opt-out in your web browser (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) and/or opt out from Google Analytics for Display Advertising or the Google Display Network. You can do so by using Google’s Ads Settings (www.google.com/settings/ads). 

## Our use of the information we collect

We use the information, including Personal Information, that we collect for the following purposes: 

  * To personalize and customize the advertising and the content you see.
  * To improve and enhance the user experience. We use tracking information to determine how well each page, station and/or channel performs overall based on aggregate user demographics and traffic patterns to those pages, stations and channels. This helps us build a better service for you.
  * To fulfill your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in polls, contests, and boards.
  * To send you information about topics or content that we think will be of interest to you based on your preferences, habits or geographic location.
  * To send you information about the latest developments and features on our TuneIn Service.
  * To provide technical support.

We may anonymize and aggregate data collected through the TuneIn Service and use it for any purpose. 

## How the information we collect is shared

We are not in the business of selling, renting or sharing Personal Information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your information, including Personal Information, with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below: 

  * With Your Permission. Information you allow us to share when you register with us, or through a subsequent affirmative election.
  * Vendor and Service Providers. Information used when we hire or partner with third parties to provide business-related services on our behalf, such as mailing information, maintaining databases, processing payments, sweepstakes management and prize fulfillment, data processing, analytics, personalization and customization of advertising, customer/support services and other products or services that we choose to make available to our registered users. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function.
  * Merger, Sale or Reorganization. We may share, transfer or sell your information in connection with a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider. We cannot control how such entities may use or disclose such information.
  * Subsidiaries and Affiliates. We may share information with our subsidiaries and affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * Social Media Sites on Your Instructions. The TuneIn Service may allow you to share information, including Personal Information, with social networking websites, such as Facebook. We do not share your Personal Information with them unless you direct the TuneIn Service to share it. Their use of the information will be governed by their privacy policies, and you may be able to modify your privacy setting on their websites.
  * Law Enforcement and Other Legal Purposes. We may share your information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect or defend our legal rights or property as well as those of our business partners, employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users or the public; (iv) protect against fraud or risk management purposes; or (v) protect against legal liability.

When you register and create a profile through the TuneIn Service, other users of the TuneIn Service may be able to see your profile information, including your profile or screen name, profile photo and any content that you post to the TuneIn Service. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of the other users who will view and use the information you post. 

## Non-Identifiable or Aggregated Data

We also receive and store certain non-personally identifiable information. Such information, which is collected passively using various technologies, cannot presently be used to specifically identify you. We may store such information itself or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by our affiliates, agents or service providers. We may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to the TuneIn Service, the number of visitors to each page of our Site, the domain names of our visitors' Internet service providers, and how our users use and interact with the TuneIn Service. Also, in an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of the TuneIn Service, we often conduct research on our customer demographics, interests and behavior based on the personal information and other information provided to us. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis. We may share this non-identifiable and aggregate data with our affiliates, agents and business partners, but this type of non-identifiable and aggregate information does not identify you personally. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to current and prospective business partners and to other third parties for other lawful purposes. 

The use and disclosure of this non-personally identifiable information is not subject to restrictions under this Privacy Policy. 

## Your Choices

You can visit the Site without providing any personal information. If you choose not to provide any personal information, you may not be able to use certain features of our TuneIn Service. 

## Exclusions

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any personal data collected by TuneIn other than Personal Information collected through the TuneIn Service. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to us through the TuneIn Service or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the TuneIn Service, such as bulletin boards (collectively, “Public Areas”), any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, “Unsolicited Information”). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and we shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, distribute and exploit such Unsolicited Information without limitation or attribution. 

## How we protect your information

We have taken reasonable steps to protect the information you provide via the TuneIn Service from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet, email or other electronic transmission is ever fully secure or error free, so you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us in this way. We do not accept liability for unintentional disclosure. 

By using the TuneIn Service or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the TuneIn Service. If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Site and/or Applications or sending an email to you. 

## Consent to processing

If you use the TuneIn Service outside of the United States, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to the transfer of your information, including Personal Information, to, and the collection and processing of such information in the United States and other countries or territories. The laws on holding such information in the United States may vary and be less stringent than laws of your state or country. 

## Children

The TuneIn Service is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Information through the TuneIn Service. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Information through the TuneIn Service without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Information to us through our TuneIn Service, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases. 

## Links to Other Web Sites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the TuneIn Service. The TuneIn Service may contain links to other web sites not operated or controlled by us (the “Third Party Sites”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the TuneIn Service do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies. 

## What are my privacy options and how can I change my settings?

_To modify your registration information:_ Once you have registered, you can change your registration information (including your email address and password). 

_To change your following list privacy setting:_ Once you have registered, you can change your profile information to make your following list more private. If you registered for the TuneIn Service prior to May 7, 2014, your following lists will be private, but your following lists will be made public once you sign in to your account. You can change your settings to make your following lists private at any time by changing your profile settings. 

_Opt out:_ Each email communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt-out" of receiving future marketing communications. In addition, if at any time you wish not to receive any future communications or you wish to have your name deleted from our email mailing lists, please contact us as indicated below. Note however, that certain communications, such as push notifications, require you to change the settings on your device if at any time you wish not to receive any future communications. Note that on occasion we send service-related announcements, such as disruption notifications, and you may not be able to opt-out of these communications. 

## English language version shall control

The English language version of this Privacy Policy is the version that governs your use of the TuneIn Service and in the event of any conflict between the English language version and a translated version, the English language version will control.

## Contact us:

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the privacy practices of TuneIn, email support@tunein.com or write to us at TuneIn, Inc., 139 Townsend Street, 4th floor, San Francisco, CA 94107, Attention: Support. 

To print out this Privacy Policy, you may visit www.tunein.com/policies/privacy/
